Welcome to our training on how to use Amazon Multi-Channel Fulfillment or MCF with Fulfillment by
Amazon or FBA.
Before we get started, you can watch Multi-Channel Fulfillment, how it works, on Seller University
or SU, to learn more about MCF.
Or go to SU for the video Multi-Channel Fulfillment, Create Fulfillment Orders to get details on
how to create single, bulk, hold, or API orders.
Now back to the training.
You can use MCF together with FBA, which allows you to consolidate your inventory into a single
pool that can be used for all your Amazon.
com and off Amazon orders.
Combining these two fulfillment solutions can help you improve your inventory turnover and prevent
stockouts.
When a customer places an order through off Amazon channels, including your brand website, other
e-commerce marketplaces, and social media stores, you can create an MCF order with Amazon.
And we'll pick that order from the inventory you've sent to a fulfillment center and pack it in
unbranded packaging.
MCF orders can be delivered as quickly as two business days, seven days a week.
Like FBA, MCF provides real-time tracking on every order, so you and your customers can monitor
the progress of orders from click to delivery.
You can also have any customer's return sent back to an Amazon fulfillment center where we'll determine
the product's status and add it to your inventory if it's still sellable.
As an Amazon seller, you can use MCF through Seller Central.
From the main menu, select Catalog, then click Add Products to upload them individually, or select
Add Products via Upload for Bulk Upload.
Bulk uploads are best used by brands or those with a professional selling account.
For a step-by-step guide on how to list products, see our video Match or Create product listings
one at a time on SU.
If you haven't sent your inventory to a fulfillment center yet, you can use the Send to Amazon workflow.
Select Inventory from the main menu in Seller Central, then click Shipments.
From the drop-down menu, click Send to Amazon.
Watch Intro to Send to Amazon on SU for more information about the workflow.
You can create and manage your orders from the MCF page in Seller Central.
Select Growth from the main menu, then click Multi-Channel Fulfillment MCF.
On the left side of the screen, you can select Place Single Order or Place Bulk Order to create
your order.
You can also click View Orders or Track Orders to manage your MCF orders.
And if you need support with an order, click Open a Support Ticket and enter your order ID, then
click Continue.
For MCF best practices, go to supplychain.
amazon.
com.
Choose Resources at the top of the page and select Knowledge Center.
Set the filter type to Guide and search for Your Guide to Seller Central.
This guide offers step-by-step instructions for order creation, inventory, returns, reports and
other topics.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon Store!